let's talk about the cryptographic hash
让我们来谈谈加密哈希函数的坚固性
function in solidity it's called to
check 256 in this video I'll explain
检查此视频中的256，我将解释什么是密码哈希函数
what a cryptographic hash function is
and I'll show your example about
我将向您展示有关使用伪随机猜游戏的示例
guessing game using the pseudo-random
nature of a cryptographic hash function
哈希函数的本质，因此首先是什么是哈希函数
so first off what is a hash function a
hash function is a function that takes
散列函数是接受任意大小的输入和输出数据的函数
in arbitrary size input and output data
of fixed sized
固定大小的哈希函数的一些属性是
some properties of a hash functions are
that it is deterministic which means
这是确定性的，这意味着如果X的哈希等于H，则
that if hash of X is equal to H then
every time you compute the hash of X and
每次您计算X的哈希值时，总等于H
then there will always equal to H the
cryptographic hash function should be
加密散列函数应快速计算，这是不可逆的
quick to compute it's irreversible this
means that given some hash age it is
意味着在给定哈希年龄的情况下，很难找到X使得X的哈希为
hard to find X such that hash of X is
equal to H small changing input changes
等于H小变化的输入会显着改变输出，这是
that output significantly and it is
collision resistant which means that
防碰撞，这意味着很难找到X和Y这样的散列
it's hard to find X & Y such that hash
of x is equal to hash of 1 now there are
的x等于1的哈希，现在有几个加密哈希函数
several cryptographic hash functions
available in civility but the one that
可以使用，但使用最多的是番茄酱
is used the most often is the ketchup
256 and to call this function you
256并调用此函数，您传递字节作为输入和一种方法
passing bytes as input and one way to
pass bytes as input to catch up to 56 is
通过调用VI点编码压缩的ABI传递字节作为输入以捕获多达56个
by calling a VI dot encode packed ABI
encode pack takes in all types of data
编码包接受所有类型的数据和任意数量的输入，例如
and any amount of inputs so for example
we could pass in a string some you end
我们可以传递一个字符串，您可以结束一些，并解决所有问题
and address it will take in all the way
put and turn it into bytes catch up 256
把它变成字节赶上256将采取ABI点的输出和
will take the output of ABI dot and
compact and turn it into a 30
压缩，然后将其转换为30个购买哈希值，我将向您展示
buying hash later I'm gonna show your
example that a small change in the input
例如，哈希函数输入的微小变化将改变
of the hash function will change the
output by a lot so I'm gonna create a
输出很多，所以在这个示例中，我将创建一个名为hash的函数
function called hash for this example
it's gonna take in some string and you
它需要输入一些字符串，然后您结束并输入一个地址，
end and an address and it's going to
return the 32 bytes of hash and inside
返回哈希的32个字节，并且在函数内部将调用ketchup 256
the function will call the ketchup 256
[Music]
[音乐]并传递文字num和地址
and passing the text num and the address
I've compiled and deployed the contract
我已经编译并部署了现在称为哈希函数的合同，并且
that's now called a hash function and
see what the output looks like so for
看看输出是什么样子，所以对于输入我要打个招呼世界
the input I'm gonna call hello world for
the first input for the number I'll put
我将在1 2 3中输入的数字的第一个输入和我将输入的地址的第一个输入
in 1 2 3 and for the address I'll just
copy the address of the contract and
复制合同的地址并粘贴到此处，我将向您展示
paste it here now I'm gonna show you
that a slight change in the input is
输入的微小变化会改变哈希值，所以首先
gonna change the hash a lot so first I'm
gonna copy this and paste it here and
将其复制并粘贴到此处，然后我将调用相同的函数，但是
then I'll call the same function but
from the hello world I'll remove the H
从hello world中，我将删除H，它表示hello world，您可以看到
and it says hello world and you can see
that we change the input by only one
我们只用一个字符更改输入，但哈希值完全是
character but the hashes are totally
different because of the property that
由于具有给定哈希值的属性，因此几乎不可能
given a hash it is almost impossible to
find the input that produced a hash we
找到产生哈希值的输入，我们可以创建一个游戏，您可以在其中猜测
can create a game where you try to guess
the word that computes to a certain edge
可以计算到特定边的单词，例如，在这里，我们有一个散列和
for example here we have a hash and the
goal of the game is to find the word
游戏的目标是找到等于该哈希值的单词，因此您将创建一个
that equals this hash so you'll create a
function called gas and for the input
函数称为gas，输入的内容是
it's going to take in a word that's
going to be hashed it's going to return
将被散列，如果输入的散列相等，则将返回true
true if the hash of the input is equal
to our target hash over here inside the
功能帐单中的目标哈希值有两个输入
function bill has two input
compared with the answer hash and then
与答案哈希进行比较，然后返回true或false
return true or false
here I've compiled and deployed a
在这里，我已经编译并部署了一个猜谜游戏合同，我将制作一个
guessing game contract and I'll make a
step the word hello hashes to the target
将单词hello hash踩到目标哈希，然后返回false
hash over here and it returns false I'll
try it terraeum and it also returns
尝试terraeum，它也返回false，所以魔术词慢慢地带有一个
false so the magic word is slowly with a
capital S and you can see that it turns
大写的S，您会看到它变成了真，因此这就是您可以创建一个
true so this is how you can create a
simple guessing game now catch up 256 is
简单的猜谜游戏现在赶上256是耐碰撞的
collision resistant
but there is one easy way that you can
但是有一种简单的方法可以创建碰撞，其中涉及使用
create a collision and it involves using
a VI dot and compact and the way you can
VI点和紧凑型，创建碰撞的方法是传递更多
create a collision is by passing more
than one dynamic data type to encode
而不是一种动态数据类型来对事实进行编码，所以这里我要对PAC进行编码
fact so here to encode PAC I'm passing
in two strings and what encode pad does
在两个字符串中，编码垫的作用是将两个字符串连接起来
is it will concatenate the two strings
so that if you pass in AAA as your first
因此，如果您将AAA作为第一个字符串，将BBB作为第二个字符串，
string and BBB as your second string a
bi encode that pact will return a BBB
bi编码该协议将返回BBB，如果您第一次输入aa
and if you pass in a a as your first
string and for the second input passing
字符串，对于第二个通过BBB的输入，再次调用了一个打包的双向对象
a BBB a bi thing called packed again
will return a BBB so notice that we have
将返回一个BBB，因此请注意，我们有两个不同的输入，但是
two different inputs but what's being
passed to the catch at 256 is the same
传递给256的渔获量是相同的，所以这意味着我们有不同的
so this will mean that we have different
inputs but the same output which is
输入但将产生哈希冲突以显示的相同输出
going to create a hash collision to show
you an actual example I'm gonna type in
你是一个实际的例子，我要输入aaa然后是BBB并获取哈希
a a a followed by BBB and get the hash
and next for the first input it's going
接下来的第一个输入将是aa，第二个输入将是
to be a a and for the second input it's
gonna be
会成为BBB，当您调用该函数时
a BBB and when you call the function
again you'll notice that the hash didn't
再次，您会注意到哈希值没有变化，因此当您编码超过
change so when you're encoding more than
one dynamic data type what you need to
一种动态数据类型，您需要在此处执行的操作不是调用和冷
do here is instead of calling and cold
pack you'll need to call encode and this
包，您将需要调用编码，这将防止哈希冲突
will prevent a hash collision from
occurring well that's all I got for this
一切顺利，这是我为这部影片所获得的一切，任何反馈或问题都让我
video any feedbacks or questions let me
know in the comments below and see you
在下面的评论中知道，然后在下一个视频中见
in the next video